<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luka Lafaye de Micheaux</title>
    <description>You&apos;ve reached my personal website.</description>
    <link>https://lukalafaye.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://lukalafaye.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 08:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 08:38:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fusion Energy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fusion could make it possible to produce very large amounts of renewable energy in the upcoming years. Currently, only 10.4% of the energy consumed worldwide is renewable according to the BP Statistical Review, a British oil extraction, refining and sales company. This means that 90.6% of the energy we consume nowadays will have to be replaced in the near future.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some people believe that nuclear power will be more than enough to cover future energy needs. Nonetheless, it is not considered a renewable energy since it requires uranium, a heavy metal which exists in limited quantities on our planet. The...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 23:38:40 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://lukalafaye.github.io/fusion-energy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukalafaye.github.io/fusion-energy/</guid>
        
        <category>fusion</category>
        
        <category>power</category>
        
        <category>energy</category>
        
        <category>eddington</category>
        
        <category>science</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Emacs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Emacs is a powerful text and source code editor with many advantages, available in GUI and CLI since 1984. In this article, I will present the advantages of the software and I will teach you some essential basics to know in order to use it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1 id=&quot;the-advantages-of-the-software&quot;&gt;The advantages of the software&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;free-and-cross-platform&quot;&gt;Free and cross-platform&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Emacs is a free tool under the GPLv3 license that does not try to make you pay unlike other publishers. In addition, it is available on GNU/Linux, MacOS, Windows, Android with Termux, FreeBSD, NetBSD, OpenBSD and Solaris! So you can try it regardless of your...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 02:00:42 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://lukalafaye.github.io/emacs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukalafaye.github.io/emacs/</guid>
        
        <category>Computing</category>
        
        <category>Text Editor</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Operating Systems</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-an-operating-system&quot;&gt;What is an operating system?&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;An operating system (often referred to as an &lt;em&gt;OS&lt;/em&gt;) is a set of very low level programs that directly control your computer’s hardware - from memory chips and hard disks to speakers, monitors, keyboards, mice and any kind of peripherals you plug on it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What are the most common OS installed on computers?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are various operating systems made for all kind of devices. We will talk about the most common ones - &lt;strong&gt;Windows, macOS, Linux&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/windows-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;windows-logo.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://windows.microsoft.com&quot;&gt;Microsoft Windows&lt;/a&gt; is currently the most popular and widely used desktop operating system....</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 01:00:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lukalafaye.github.io/operating-systems/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukalafaye.github.io/operating-systems/</guid>
        
        <category>Computing</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How does the brain work?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people know that the brain is divided in two halves called hemispheres by the cerebral fissure… But did you know that it is the left side of the brain that controls the right side of your body and vice versa? The brain is a very complicated organ, which we are going to discover and explain to you now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Firstly, you need to know that what you see when you think of a brain is only the very surface. What you do imagine is usually the cerebral cortex, a wrinkly and pink, flesh like tissue, the exterior part of the...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 01:00:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lukalafaye.github.io/brain-function/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukalafaye.github.io/brain-function/</guid>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        <category>Information</category>
        
        <category>science</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How does the nervous system work?</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-does-the-brain-control-our-body&quot;&gt;How does the brain control our body?&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;From the embryo, 4 weeks into pregnancy, to the birth, and then up to death, the brain stays the boss and most important part of the body. All the other organs and body parts are dependant upon the brain, just like a puppet depends upon the puppet master. The brain is responsible for everything in a human being: from something such as your movements, up to your mood, to the pain you feel, the emotions you experience… Everything comes and goes from up there!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1 id=&quot;the-nervous-system&quot;&gt;The Nervous System&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;So how does the...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 01:00:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lukalafaye.github.io/nervous-system-function/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukalafaye.github.io/nervous-system-function/</guid>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        <category>Information</category>
        
        <category>Nervous System</category>
        
        <category>science</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>At which temperature does water freeze?</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;surprise&quot;&gt;Surprise!&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve all been taught that fresh water freezes at 32 degrees F, 0°C, 273.15 K. However, it is possible to keep water liquid at lower temperatures! Scientists have cooled water down to -42 °C in labs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-supercooling&quot;&gt;What is supercooling?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Supercooling is a state where liquids do not solidify even below their normal freezing point!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A good example of this phenomenon is found everyday in meteorology: clouds in high altitude are an accumulation of supercooled droplets of water below their freezing point. How is that possible?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In order to freeze water, you need to give it a small...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 01:00:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lukalafaye.github.io/supercooled-water/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukalafaye.github.io/supercooled-water/</guid>
        
        <category>Science</category>
        
        <category>Mathematics</category>
        
        <category>Information</category>
        
        <category>science</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can fish change sex?</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Yes!&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fish have incredible ways to ensure that their genetic diversity continues to survive and that they stay well adapted to the environment. Almost 500 species of fish (or 2% of their population) possesses the ability to change sex naturally! Their phenotype is also much influenced by the environment. For instance, warmer temperatures tend to make female fish change into male and experiments proved that only 6 ng/L of 17α-ethynylestradiol (substance used in contraceptive pills) leads to the feminisation of freshwater fish!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are three main types of fish that have the ability to naturally switch sex: &lt;strong&gt;protogynous&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;protandrous&lt;/strong&gt;...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 01:00:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://lukalafaye.github.io/sequential-hermaphroditism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukalafaye.github.io/sequential-hermaphroditism/</guid>
        
        <category>Fish</category>
        
        <category>Information</category>
        
        <category>science</category>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
